<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Interpretation | Dominic Magirr</title>
    <link>/tags/interpretation/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tags/interpretation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Interpretation</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Interpretation</title>
      <link>/tags/interpretation/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big phase 3 studies as &#34;successes&#34; or &#34;failures&#34;</title>
      <link>/post/big-phase-3-studies-as-successes-or-failures/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/big-phase-3-studies-as-successes-or-failures/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;I came across &lt;a href=&#34;http://heartfailure.onlinejacc.org/content/7/11/993&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;http://heartfailure.onlinejacc.org/content/biography&#34;&gt;Christopher M. O’Connor&lt;/a&gt; calling for a change in the way we interpret statistical significance. This is not a new debate, but I found it interesting because:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Many clinicians in the community believe that the p-value provides a simple, reliable, objective triage tool for separating truth from the unimportant.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trials that are written off as “failures” when p=0.051 (or something else just above 0.05)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trials that are claimed as “successes” when p=0.049 (or something else just below 0.05)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The piece by O’Connor focusses on (1.). I think, in practice that (1.) is very rarely a problem. However, (2.) could be a problem. Therefore I think the final advice is sound, but he gets there from the wrong direction. Actually, he doesn’t go far enough….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me explain…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s referring specifically to &lt;em&gt;very big&lt;/em&gt; phase 3 clinical studies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everyone seemed to agree with it, whereas I don’t (fully).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://citeseerx.ist.psu.edu/viewdoc/download?doi=10.1.1.601.3757&amp;amp;rep=rep1&amp;amp;type=pdf&#34;&gt;CHARM study&lt;/a&gt; is used as an example, where candesartan was compared to placebo in a randomized trial with 3023 patients. The primary endpoint was time-to-event, where the event was “cardiovascular death of admission to hospital for chronic heart failure”. The result was a hazard ratio of 0.86 with 95% confidence interval of (0.74, 1.00) and a p-value of 0.051.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O’Connor says, “given this finding, candesartan did not meet its primary endpoint and was not integrated into the guidelines for potential benefit in patients with HF”. He is making the point that if the result had been just slightly different, such that p=0.049, then the interpretation would have changed completely from a &lt;em&gt;failed&lt;/em&gt; study to &lt;em&gt;successful&lt;/em&gt; study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the face of it, this cliff-edge change of opinion does appear completely ridiculous. However, I think when you consider the wider context, it &lt;em&gt;may still&lt;/em&gt; be ridiculous, but often it’s not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;translation-to-a-better-measure-of-treatment-effect&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Translation to a ‘better’ measure of treatment effect&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O’Connor makes the valid point that interpretation should be based on effect sizes and confidence intervals. However, what I think is missing in this article:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;the-sponsor-has-already-thought-about-clinical-relevance-at-the-design-stage&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The sponsor has already thought about clinical relevance at the design stage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;conclusions&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
