<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Authors | Dominic Magirr</title>
    <link>/authors/</link>
      <atom:link href="/authors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Authors</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Authors</title>
      <link>/authors/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/admin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a medical statistician. I&amp;rsquo;m interested in the design, analysis and interpretation of clinical trials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I originally planned to study medicine. However, after doing some work experience and realizing how difficult that path would be, I decided to do a maths degree. Towards the end of my studies I was fortunate to see a careers talk on Medical Statistics that led me to Lancaster University to do their MSc course &amp;ndash; a fantastic year, and I carried on to do a PhD. My research was on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;group sequential trials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;multiple hypothesis testing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;adaptive designs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stayed in Lancaster a little longer, and also had a wonderful year at the Medical University of Vienna. This time allowed me to publish some more papers, teach, and start my statistical consultancy career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came back to the UK in 2015 to work at AstraZeneca. For two years, I worked in the early-phase oncology group, as part of clinical teams, contributing to the design of trials, and overseeing the statistical analyses conducted by CRO partners. For a further year, I worked as an internal statistical consultant as part of AstraZeneca&amp;rsquo;s Statistical Innovation team. This was an intense, but rewarding, experience that allowed me to work on trials in many different therapy areas. A highlight was working on &lt;a href=&#34;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1002/sim.8186&#34;&gt;new methods for dealing with non-proportional hazards in immuno-oncology&lt;/a&gt;. (Preprint &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1807.11097.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since January 2019 I have been working at a start-up company &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ccg.ai&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cambridge Cancer Genomics&lt;/a&gt;, where I have become very interested in statistical modelling of longitudinal circulating-tumour DNA measurements.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robert Ford</title>
      <link>/authors/robert-ford/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/robert-ford/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
